<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://spongbb258.github.io</id>
    <title>Yichen Zhu&apos;s blog</title>
    <updated>2022-06-10T01:00:34.803Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://spongbb258.github.io"/>
    <link rel="self" href="https://spongbb258.github.io/atom.xml"/>
    <subtitle>Welcome!</subtitle>
    <logo>https://spongbb258.github.io/images/avatar.png</logo>
    <icon>https://spongbb258.github.io/favicon.ico</icon>
    <rights>All rights reserved 2022, Yichen Zhu&apos;s blog</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[My climate story!]]></title>
        <id>https://spongbb258.github.io/post/project-3/</id>
        <link href="https://spongbb258.github.io/post/project-3/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-06-04T10:49:05.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Introduction:</strong><br>
When I first joined my first college writing course and was informed we are going to learn about the climate crisis, I was wondering how we were going to be taught about the climate crisis. Would this course simply teach us that a climate crisis is happening and we should take actions, just like what I have learned in High School? But this course taught me about the climate crisis in new aspects that I never taught before. For example, how we could discuss the climate crisis with others.  Thus, for this article, I am going to tell my climate story based on what I have learned.</p>
<p><strong>My climate story:</strong><br>
When I was little, I remembered I grew up in the countryside of Beijing. I used to chase chickens that belonged to my grandma, played with clay or sand at my neighbors’ house , or walk on a river with my bare feet. I loved the summer back when I was in the countryside. The wind was cool and clouds almost ‘occupied’ the whole sky. When the sun was too bright, we sat under the big tree and relaxed.<br>
But the environment was always changing. When I moved downtown,  I realized how there were more skyscrapers and tall buildings compared to the countryside. Less trees and dirty river closer to our apartment. But I still loved spending time with my friend outside, we loved running in the rain like crazy, or building a snowman or having a snowball fight after a snow. I still remembered how excited I was the first time I saw snow.<br>
However, the climate changed rapidly when I grew up. For the first time, I started to see less snow, dirty rain and also foggy weather. The summer was warmer than before, and even a sandstorm was occured for the first time, which was only heard from my parents or news. For the first time, I started to believe that the climate crisis is happening.<br>
<img src="https://spongbb258.github.io/post-images/1654822592076.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
-Image credit VCG.com</p>
<p>Later on, I learned more about the climate crisis from different sources, and I realized that one of the problems about climate crisis is that some countries or areas that are poor cannot live without fossil fuels and they could not or they did not have a chance to learn about climate crisis, and another problem is that some people do not believe in climate crisis, or I have to say they do not believe in scientists, and their claim.</p>
<p><strong>Consequences:</strong><br>
When talking about the climate crisis, some people may ask why they should care about the crisis, and how the climate crisis is related to them, and some people may even think that climate crisis is a conspiracy from government or scientist. However, based on the reports from NASA, we are experiencing more droughts and heat waves, rising of sea level and so many other changes.<br>
<img src="https://spongbb258.github.io/post-images/1654822327454.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy"><br>
-Image credit NASA</p>
<p>Thus, how we change to duel with  the climate crisis is important. Because earth would not be destroyed by us, humans.  Think about dinosaurs, and so many other species that were distinct, the humans are just ‘visitors’ that have lived a short life on earth, compared to the history of earth. If humans no longer existed on earth, earth can be recovered and have the next species to live on earth. Thus, to me, I feel like the reason I try to inform people about the climate crisis is for my future children or the next generation. Because I hope they can spend their childhood embracing nature, just like me, and less disaster in the future will be brought because of the climate crisis. Like the comparison in my story, I used to love spending my time outside with my friend, but at one point in my life, I could not build a snowman in the winter anymore, because of the pollution of the particles in the air.</p>
<p><strong>My proposals:</strong><br>
In my second project of my writing course, we were asked how we could get people to respond to the climate crisis. In this post, I would suggest the following points:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>I would suggest education would start teaching or simply inform people about the climate crisis earlier, and I think letting children access the climate crisis is also important.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Besides, I think rhetorical listening, which I learned from this course could also be informed to people, not just children. Because I think rhetorical listening is a really good idea to let people hear opinions from the people who hold the opposite position with them.</p>
</li>
</ol>
]]></content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Project 3 working in progrsss]]></title>
        <id>https://spongbb258.github.io/post/project-3-working-in-progrsss/</id>
        <link href="https://spongbb258.github.io/post/project-3-working-in-progrsss/">
        </link>
        <updated>2022-06-03T01:47:45.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>1</p>
]]></content>
    </entry>
</feed>